Guide to the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee 40th anniversary conference videocassette tapes, 2000 RL.10136
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee 40th anniversary conference videocassette tapes
2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.)
RL.10136
0.4 Linear Feet
Sixteen digital videocassette tapes documenting the 13 April 2000 conference, "We Who Believe in Freedom Cannot Rest: Ella J. Baker ("Miss Baker") and the Birth of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee," held at Shaw University, in Raleigh, NC.
Collection Overview
Sixteen digital videocassette tapes documenting the 13 April 2000 conference, "We Who Believe in Freedom Cannot Rest: Ella J. Baker ('Miss Baker') and the Birth of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee," held at Shaw University, in Raleigh, NC. The conference celebrated the organization's 40th anniversary. The Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (or SNCC, pronounced "snick") was one of the primary institutions of the American Civil Rights Movement in the 1960s. It emerged in April of 1960 from student meetings led by Baker and held at Shaw. Some of the original student members were organizers of sit-ins at segregated lunch counters in the southern United States. Its purpose then was to coordinate the use of nonviolent direct action to attack segregation and other forms of racism.
SNCC played a leading role in the Freedom Rides, the 1963 March on Washington, Mississippi Freedom Summer and the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party over the next few years. In the later part of the 1960s, SNCC focused on Black Power, and then fighting against the Vietnam War. In 1969, SNCC officially changed its name to the Student National Coordinating Committee to reflect the broadening of its strategies.
Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Collection of African and African-American Documentation.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged by original tape number.
Historical note
The Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (or SNCC, pronounced "snick") was one of the primary institutions of the American Civil Rights Movement in the 1960s. It emerged in April of 1960 from student meetings led by Baker and held at Shaw. Some of the original student members were organizers of sit-ins at segregated lunch counters in the southern United States. Its purpose then was to coordinate the use of nonviolent direct action to attack segregation and other forms of racism. SNCC played a leading role in the Freedom Rides, the 1963 March on Washington, Mississippi Freedom Summer and the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party over the next few years. In the later part of the 1960s, SNCC focused on Black Power, and then fighting against the Vietnam War. In 1969, SNCC officially changed its name to the Student National Coordinating Committee to reflect the broadening of its strategies.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.). 40th Anniversary Conference (2000: Raleigh, N.C.); Mini-DV; Audiovisual materials; Baker, Ella; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.)
- Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee 40th anniversary conference videocassette tapes, 2000 April; 1
  - Tape 1, 2000 April; 1
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0001)
  - Tape 2, 2000 April; 2
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0002)
  - Tape 3, 2000 April; 3
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0003)
  - Tape 4, 2000 April; 4
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0004)
  - Tape 5, 2000 April; 5
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0005)
  - Tape 6, 2000 April; 6
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0006)
  - Tape 7, 2000 April; 7
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0007)
  - Tape 8, 2000 April; 8
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0008)
  - Tape 9, 2000 April; 9
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0009)
  - Tapes 10 and 11, 2000 April; 10
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0010)
  - Tape 12, 2000 April; 11
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0011)
  - Tape 13, 2000 April; 12
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0012)
  - Tape 14, 2000 April; 13
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0013)
  - Workshop, 2000 April; 14
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0014)
  - Wrap up, 2000 April; 15
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0015)
  - 4/2000, 2000 April; 16
    - Original mini-dv backup copy (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10136-MDV-0016)